Now, the last model took quite a while to train,
上个模型训练时间很长
and there are some ways that we can speed up this process.
其实有一些加快训练流程的方式
In this video, I'll talk about one such method which is called negative sampling.
在本视频中 我将介绍一种方式 叫做负采样
So, this is a new notebook,
虽然这是一个新的 notebook
but it contains basically the same info as
但是其中包含的信息
our previous notebook including this architecture diagram.
与上个 notebook 很类似 包括这个结构示意图
This is our current architecture where we have a softmax layer on the output,
这是当前结构 我们对输出应用了 softmax 层级
and since we're working with tens of thousands of words,
因为我们处理的是成千上万个字词
the softmax layer is going to have tens of thousands of units.
所以 softmax 层级将包含成千上万个单元
But with any one input,
但是对于任何一个输入
we're really going to have one true context target.
只有一个真实的上下文目标
What that means is, when we train,
也就是说 当我们训练模型时
we're going to be making very small changes to the weights between
虽然我们只关心一个真实输出
these two layers even though we only have one true output that we care about.
但是这两个层级之间的权重都会轻微变化
So, very few of the weights are actually going to be updated in a meaningful way.
所以我们只会以有意义的方式更新很少的权重
Instead what we can do is approximate the loss from the softmax layer,
我们可以从 softmax 层级逼近损失
and we do this by only updating a small subset of all the weights at once.
方法是一次仅更新一小部分权重
We'll update the weights for what we know to be the correct target output,
我们将更新已知正确的目标输出对应的权重
but then we'll only update a small number of
但同时更新一小部分错误或噪点目标
incorrect or noise targets usually around 100 or so as opposed to 60,000.
通常大约为 100 个 而不是全部的 60,000 个
This process is called negative sampling.
这个流程称为负采样
To implement this, there are two main modifications we need to make to our model.
为了实现该功能 我们需要对模型做出两大更改
First, since we're not taking the softmax output over all the words,
首先 我们不对所有字词应用 softmax 层级
we're really only concerned with one output one at a time.
每次只关心一个输出
Similar to how we used an embedding layer to map
与使用嵌入层
an input word to a row of embedding weights,
将输入字词映射到一行嵌入权重相似
we can now use another embedding layer to
现在我们可以使用另一个嵌入层
map the output words to a row of hidden weights.
将输出字词映射到一行隐藏权重
So, we'll have two embedding layers,
所以我们将有两个嵌入层
one for input words and one for output words.
一个针对输入字词 一个针对输出字词
Second, we have to use a modified loss function that only cares about
其次 我们需要使用另一种损失函数
the true target and a small subset of noisy and correct target context words,
该函数只关心真实目标和一部分有噪点的及正确的目标上下文字词
and that's this big loss function here.
也就是这个损失函数
It's a little heavy on notation,
公式比较长
so I'll go over it one part at a time.
我来介绍下每部分的含义
Let's take a look at the first term.
先看看第一项
We can see that this is a negative log operation,
这是一个负对数运算
and this little loop, this lowercase sigma is a sigmoid activation function.
这个小写的 σ 表示 S 型激活函数
A sigmoid activation function scales any input from a range from zero to one.
S 型激活函数会将任何输入的范围缩放到 0-1 之间
So, let's look at the input inside the parentheses.
我们看看括号里的输入
UW0 transpose is the embedding vector for our output target word.
uw0 转置矩阵表示输出目标字词的嵌入向量
So, this is the embedding vector that we know as
它表示对于给定输入字词来说
the correct contexts target for a given input word.
已知正确的上下文目标字词对应的嵌入向量
This T here is the transpose symbol.
这个 T 是转置符号
Then we have VWI which is the embedding vector for our input word.
vwi 表示输入字词的嵌入向量
In general, you will indicate an output embedding and V are input.
通常用 u 表示输出嵌入向量 用 v 表示输入嵌入向量
If you remember from doing cosine similarity
之前计算 cosine_similarity 时提到
a transpose multiplication like this is equivalent to doing a.product operation.
这样的转置乘法等效于点积运算
So, this whole first term is same that we take the log sigmoid of the.product
所以整个第一项的含义是计算正确输出字词向量与输入字词向量的点积
of our correct output word vector with our input word vector,
然后对点积结果应用 Log-Sigmoid 函数
and this represents our correct target loss.
这部分表示正确目标损失
Next, we want to sample our outputs and get some noisy target words,
接下来我们需要对输出进行采样并获得一些噪点目标字词
and that's what the second part of this equation is all about.
这就是第二部分的作用
So, let's look at this piece by piece.
逐个讲解下
This capital sigma means we're going to take a sum over all of our words WI.
大写的 Σ 表示对所有字词 wi 求和
This P and W indicates that these words are drawn from a noise distribution.
Pn(w) 表示这些字词来自噪点分布
The noise distribution is our vocabulary of
噪点分布是指
words that are not in the context of our input word.
不在输入字词的上下文中的词汇表字词
In effect, we want to randomly sample words from
也就是说 我们将从词汇表中随机抽取样本字词
our vocabulary to get these noisy irrelevant target words.
来获得这些不相关的噪点目标字词
So P and W is
所以 Pn(w)
an arbitrary probability distribution which
是一个任意概率分布
means we can get to decide how to weight the words that we're sampling.
我们可以决定对要抽样的字词设定多大的权重
This could be a uniform distribution where we sample all words with
它可以是一个均匀分布 即抽取所有字词的概率是相等的
equal probability or it could be according to
也可以根据每个字词
the frequency that each word shows up in our text corpus,
出现在文本词汇表中的频率进行采样
the unigram distribution UW.
即一元模型分布 U(w)
In fact the authors of the negative sampling paper found
负采样论文的作者们发现
the best distribution to be a unigram distribution raised to the three-fourths.
最佳分布为 U(w)^(3/4)
Then we get to this last part which looks very similar to our first term.
这是最后一部分 看起来和第一项很相似
This takes the log sigmoid of the negated.product between a noise vector UWI,
这部分会计算噪点向量 U(wi) 与之前的输入向量之间的点积
and our input vector from before.
并对结果取负数 然后再应用 Log Sigmoid 函数
To give you an intuition for what this whole loss is doing here,
解释下整个损失函数的作用
remember that this sigmoid function returns a probability between zero and one.
这个 S 型函数会返回 0-1 之间的概率
So, the first term in this loss is going to push the probability that
所以第一项会促使
our network will predict the correct context word towards one.
网络预测正确上下文字词的概率接近 1
In the second term, since we're negating the sigmoid input,
在第二项里 由于我们对 S 型函数的输入取负值
we're pushing the summed probabilities that our network will
所以我们会促使
predict the incorrect noisy words towards zero.
网络预测错误噪点字词的概率之和接近 0
Okay. So next, I'll present your task which will be to
Ok在下道练习中
define this negative sampling model in code.
你将用代码定义这个负采样模型